EXPERIENCE

Intermediate Backend Developer

Zenhub, Vancouver, Canada January 2023 - April 2024

- Developed AI-powered features leveraging LLMs, embedding models, and vector databases to enhance system intelligence and UX.
- Streamlined codebase through refactoring efforts, resulting in a more maintainable and scalable architecture.
- Integrated third-party APIs into existing systems to extend product capabilities without reinventing the wheel.
- Tuned systems to boost performance.

Infrastructure Systems Engineer

Meta (Facebook), Dublin, Ireland October 2020 - November 2022

- Deployed firmware across the entire Meta server fleet.
- Monitor Meta server fleet health metrics and resolved production system failures during on-call rotations.
- Spearheaded the development of an internal tooling to replace the legacy version, resulting in a significant improvement in performance, scalability and user experience.
- Implemented intuitive UI solutions for internal tooling, streamlining workflows and enhancing efficiency across multiple teams.
- Managed and mentored an intern, overseeing their professional development and contributing to the company's talent cultivation.

iOS Software Developer (Internship)

Ecobee, Toronto, Canada September 2018 - December 2018

- Won the company-wide hackathon by implementing multi-user support using Swift for the iOS app, Express and Node.js on the back-end where owners can share home devices with tenants using a one-time-pin verification, customize tenant usage limitations and set tenant expiry dates. The prototype was adopted by the iOS team as a reference for the new smart home feature.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality products on tight deadlines.

PROJECTS

Door RFID Security Hack

- Hacked a building security system by analyzing communication between the door scanner and security controller using an oscilloscope.
- Built a \$5 bug that could be soldered to any scanner to grant entry access and spy on transmission.
- Stored user-entry signature in a Firebase Realtime NoSQL database and hosted a node.js backend service on AWS EC2.
- Wrote an iOS app with BLE and proximity sensor that unlocks the door by sending details over the security system using the bug to hi-jack communication lines.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Canada, Graduated: May 2020

Lester Lim

Software Engineer

Vancouver, Canada +1 778-239-0073 lesterlimwh@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lesterlimwh www.github.com/lesterlimwh

PROFICIENT TECH

Python | Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL | Docker

FAMILIAR TECH

Python | C# | Unity XR | JavaScript PHP Hack | Swift | ML | LLMs Embeddings | Vector Databases GraphQL | React | React Native MySQL | AWS | Azure | Kubernetes

ABOUT ME

I love solving problems through software engineering. After studying computer science at the University of Waterloo, I started my professional career in 2019 as an Infrastructure Systems Engineer at Meta. While I am most proficient in backend development, I've experienced various fields of software engineering throughout my career - e.g. deploying software at scale, building AI-powered services, building mobile apps, UI design and tinkering with IoT products. During my free time, I enjoy working with AR/VR as a hobby.

LANGUAGES

English (Native)
Chinese (Intermediate)
Japanese (Intermediate)

Please contact me for references.